STANISLAV ALEXOVIČ

Software developer

Slovakia, EU

▼ stanislav.alexovic@gmail.com

Profile

With 15 years of experience as a seasoned programmer, my career objective is to develop clean and readable programs, placing a strong emphasis on understanding underlying functionality to ensure efficient program design and implementation. I am highly motivated to continuously expand my knowledge abreast of emerging and stay technologies. Ī am Moreover, passionate about sharing my expertise and actively collaborating with others to cultivate a culture of knowledge exchange and growth.

Skills

- C++
- Python
- ROS, ROS2
- RabbitMQ
- Docker
- Git
- Visual Studio Code
- Linux

Education

Ph.D.

Electrical engineering
Technical University of Košice,

iii 09/2020 – 08/2023

M.S.

Secondary Technical School of Electrical Engineering.

iii 09/1999 – 06/2003

Experience

Photoneo / Brightpick

Senior software developer

- Created a fleet management system for an automatic warehouse, enabling coordination and management of multiple mobile robots. # Python
- Developed software for a mobile robot, including APIs, communication with hardware, processing sensor inputs, and pose localization. # C++, ROS, Docker, SLAM

ComAp

iii 10/2018 – 10/2019

Embedded programmer

- Implemented a PLC interpreter and PLC blocks. # C
- Refactored the MODBUS client. # C, MODBUS

ESET

iii 09/2008 – 10/2018

Software developer

- Developed a push notification system, including client-side implementation and MQTT protocol integration.
 # C++, MQTT
- Maintained integration of an antispam engine into the ESET Smart Security product. # C, C++
- Created a DNS tunnel module capable of transferring data over DNS in situations where other network protocols were restricted. # C++
- Developed a web-based information system for handling incoming antispam statistics, including processing, storing, filtering, and displaying. # Python, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Implemented a standalone application for creating live CD/DVD or USB systems, known as ESET SysRescue Live.
 # C++, QT
- Developed a standalone application for activating preinstalled ESET products. # C++, MFC
- Maintained the installer for ESET products. # C++, MSI, WiX